A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Counsel's Office, Series 10 FA358
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Michael Whiteman, 1963-1974; 4; 80 Document Box(es)
  - Program - Crime Control, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 282)
    1) Child abuse, press release 2) criminal offenders, memos, crime control council report, press releases news articles 3) traffic scofflaw, memos 4) air cargo security, memos 5) explosives, memos, press release, draft legislation 6) general, memos, press release 7) gun safety, memos
  - Program - Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs, 1970; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 283)
    1) Methadone, memos 2) Temporary Commission to Evaluate Drug Laws -- memos, correspondence, press releases 3) Toxicology and Drug Center, proposed legislation, press release
  - Program - Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs, 1970; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 284)
    4) War on drugs press releases, transcript of news conference, correspondence
  - Program - Narcotics and Dangerous Drugs, 1970; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 27, Folder 284.1)
    5) General: press releases, memos and correspondence, program notes
  - Program - Community Development, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 285)
    1) Authorization of savings institution loans on mobile homes 2) expansion of Home Owners Purchase Endorsement (HOME) 3) proposal for housing development of Floyd Bennett Field 4) general, press release, CBS-TV editorial 5) residential mortgage program, $60,000,000 pool for mortgages on new home
  - Program - Community Development (Box 28, Folder 286)
    Housing press releases, background studies, correspondence, program suggestions.
  - Program - Transportation (Box 28, Folder 287)
    Mass transportation program, draft of annual message, emergency subsidy to Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) legislation, program bill, background memo.
  - Program - Transportation, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 288)
    1) Joint planning -- program memos 2) relocation assistance -- program memos, press release 3) public parking facilities -- program memo, press release 4) highway safety -- correspondence, program memo, press release 5) New York-New Jersey Airport Commission -- correspondence 6) general -- notes, program memos
  - Program - Department of Parks and Recreation, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 289)
    Proposal notes -- new department.
  - Program - Operating Aid for Non-profit Institutions, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 290)
    Annual message materials, Council on the Arts.
  - Program, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 291)
    1) Governors Environmental Board -- letter from Albany Mayor Erastus Corning 2) environmental conservation -- endangered species -- correspondence 3) environmental conservation -- water pollution
  - Program - Department of Environmental Conservation, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 292)
    Studies, proposals, memos, press releases, etc. re: creation of department.
  - Program, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 293)
    1. Solid waste disposal -- program note 2. abandoned cars -- correspondence, program notes, news articles
  - Program - State Nature and Historical Preserve, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 294)
    National Governors Conference report, program notes, news article.
  - Program - Minimum Wage and Social Insurance, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 295)
    1. Increase minimum wage from $1.65 to $1.80 2. increase maximum weekly benefits under workers' compensation, unemployment benefits, and disability benefits by $10.00, correspondence, reports, program notes, proposed bills
  - Program - Economic Development of Cities, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 296)
    1. Job Development Authority loans for multi-tenant structures, program suggestions 2. expansion of Urban Job Incentive Program, press releases, program bill
  - Program - Rural Economy, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 297)
    Tax incentives for business investment in rural poverty areas.
  - Program - Professional Corporations, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 298)
    Proposed bill.
  - Program - Manpower Training, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 299)
    Work incentives for home relief recipients.
  - Program - Elective Franchise, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 300)
    1. Election law calendar 2. reorganization of New York City Board of Elections 3. elimination of property requirements for voting 4. voting for 18-hear-olds 5. general -- program notes, letter from Assembly man Andrew Stein proposing Election Reform Commission
  - Program - Government Effectiveness, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 301)
    1. Employee salary plan: press release, report on improvements 1967-1969 2. municipal ethics: program note, press release 3. per capita aid: press release, commission proposal, program note, advisory commission on intergovernmental relations report 4. administrative procedures act: program note, proposed bill 5. temporary state commission to modernize the courts: memos, correspondence, program notes, press release 6. improvement of assessment practices: 1969 bill, program notes, memos, press release 7. temporary state commission to modernize laws of eminent domain, program note, memo re: sponsorship
  - Program - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 302)
    1. Atlantic Avenue: copy of portion of bill sent to Sen. Stewart 2. constitutional tax and debt limits: memorandum 3. contraband cigarettes: letter to Robert Douglass from Department of Tax 4. grave diggers: research on emergency legislation to end strike, draft legislation, press release
  - Program - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 303)
    Off-track betting: drafts of legislation, reports correspondence.
  - Program - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 304)
    Sheriffs' 20-year retirement bill.
  - Program - Miscellaneous - Tax Conformity, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 305)
    Memos and reports on efforts in New York of Federal Tax Reform and Relief Act of 1969.
  - Program - Miscellaneous, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 306)
    1. Taylor Law changes, memoranda 2. Teachers Retirement Program: memo from S. G. Hopkins to Robert Douglass 3. Waterfront Commission: program bill, memo
  - Program, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 307)
    1. Constitutional amendments 2. departmental proposals 3. annual message breakdown and status sheets 4. industrial growth -- office for service industries -- memo 5. employment -- collective negotiations disputes
  - Program - Health Care, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 308)
    Universal health care program bills, drafts, memos; Nelson A. Rockefeller speech at Einstein Medical College March 23, 1971; Pamphlet: "1970 Health Legislation" by Community Services Society of New York.
  - Program - Health, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 309)
    1. Hospital and Nursing Home Loan Program 2. group medical practice -- nonprofit medical corporations 3. physicians assistants 4. family planing 5. abortion ("not this year")
  - Program - Primary and Secondary Education, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 310)
    Blaine Amendment repeal (aid to non-public schools).
  - Program - Primary and Secondary Education, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 311)
    School aid -- present formula.
  - Program - Higher Education, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 312)
    College loans, youth clearinghouse, student interns.
  - Program, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 313)
    1. Special messages and bills -- residency requirements, mandatory work 2. federal family assistance plan -- program bill
  - Program, October 20, 1970, February 1971 (Box 30, Folder 314)
    Jobs and training -- social insurance -- unemployment: correspondence, reports, studies on unemployment insurance.
  - Program, March 1971 (Box 30, Folder 315)
    Jobs and training -- social insurance -- unemployment: tables, studies on unemployment.
  - Program - Community Development Bond Issue, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 316)
    Reports, memos, draft legislation, program bills.
  - Program - Housing, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 317)
    Program notes, correspondence, memos, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release.
  - Program - Transportation, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 318)
    1. Highway construction and spending, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release 2. financing mass transportation -- reports, vote tally on $2.5 billion transportation bond issue
  - Program - Eminent Domain, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 319)
    Interim Report of State Commission on Eminent Domain, staff memo.
  - Program - Crime and Narcotics, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 320)
    Press releases, annual message notes and drafts, memos, news articles.
  - Program - Crime Insurance, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 321)
    Draft proposal from Insurance Department, memos.
  - Program - Crime, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 322)
    Cigarettes, correspondence, and reports re: bootlegging and tax increases.
  - Program - Safety in the Streets, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 323)
    Safe Streets Act, press release, program note, proposed legislation, memos.
  - Program - Prosecution, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 324)
    1. Firearms safety -- program bill 2. explosives control -- colleges -- press release and memo 3. tax evasion -- program note 4. drug law revision (marijuana) -- proposed amendments for sentencing
  - Program - Courts, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 325)
    Court reform, memos and studies.
  - Program - Courts, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 326)
    No fault insurance, background materials, correspondence, position papers.
  - Program - Narcotics, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 327)
    1. Expansion of local youthful drug abuse program -- press release 2. Drug Abuse Institute -- memo from Health Commissioner Ingraham 3. Increased law enforcement personnel -- memo from Howard Shapiro
  - Program - Environment, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 328)
    Pollution enforcement studies and program recommendations, press releases.
  - Program - Pure Waters, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 329)
    Phosphates -- lobbying papers, program memo, press release, program bill, toxic metal discharge press release.
  - Program - Air Pollution - Motor Vehicles, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 330)
    Press releases and memo re: unleaded gasoline.
  - Program - Solid Waste, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 331)
    1. Disposal equipment financing, program memo 2. billboard controls -- press release, program note and bill
  - Program - Preserving the Adirondacks, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 332)
    Studies and reports -- Temporary Study Commission on the Future of the Adirondacks, Department of Environmental Conservation, notes, proposed bills, correspondence, press releases.
  - Program - Parks and Recreation, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 333)
    Commissioner's program proposals, notes.
  - Program - Industrial Growth - Power Plant Site, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 334)
    Reports, correspondence, legislation.
  - Program - Federal Action, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 335)
    Revenue sharing -- memos, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release.
  - Program - Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 336)
    1. Executive reorganization -- chart 2. Administrative Procedure Act -- Department of Civil Service memo
  - Program - Agricultural Districting, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 337)
    Memos, proposed legislation.
  - Program - Bank Redistricting, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 338)
    Proposed legislation, memos and correspondence.
  - Program - Bond Banks, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 339)
    Proposed bill, memo in support.
  - Program - Creation of Community Antenna Television (CATV) Commission, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 340)
    Proposed legislation, reports, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, correspondence.
  - Program - Comptroller's Military Service Credit Bill, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 341)
    Proposed legislation, memos.
  - Program - Consumer Protection, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 342)
    Proposals (Betty Furness), 1970, staff memos, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release (October 15, 1970), drafts of special message to legislature.
  - Program - Full Crew Repeal, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 343)
    Whiteman memo to Nelson A. Rockefeller re: status of bills.
  - Program - Human Rights, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 344)
  - Program - Insurance (Crime), 1971 (Box 33, Folder 345)
  - Program - Office of Employee Relations (OER) - Management/Confidential Group, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 346)
    Memos and draft legislation re: exemptions from Civil Service definitions in Taylor law.
  - Program - Off-Track Betting, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 347)
  - Program - Local Real Property Taxes - Penn Central Bankruptcy, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 348)
  - Program - Rent Control, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 349)
    Memos, analysis of appropriate equalization rates, legislation.
  - Program - Retirement, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 350)
    Robert R. Douglass December 16, 1969 memo to Nelson A. Rockefeller, R. L. Dunham March 1, 1970 memo to Robert R. Douglass.
  - Program - Taylor Law I, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 351)
    Agenda, drafts of bills.
  - Program - Taylor Law II, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 352)
    Memos, reports, Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA) strike.
  - Program - Waterfront Commission, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 353)
    Proposed rail connection to John F. Kennedy Airport and New Jersey, waterfront safety.
  - Program - Welfare Residency, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 354)
    Attorney General's briefs in federal lawsuit challenging constitutionality of residency requirement.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 355)
    Marijuana legislation, memo re: status of amendments.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 356)
    Minimum salary bills, 1971 -- C. Webb; proposal to repeal schedules for state and city university personnel.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 357)
    Howard Shapiro miscellaneous correspondence.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 358)
    Municipal Police Training Council -- copy of 1966 regulations, draft of new regulations, press release.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 359)
    New York City Commission (Scott): legislation establishing Commission, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, memos, news articles.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 360)
    New York City pre-sentenced inmates: to be housed by State Corrections, memos, draft agreement.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 361)
    1971 New York City tax proposals: Mayor Lindsay on city-state relations.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 362)
    New York City/Metropolitan Transit Authority construction fund, memos, legislation.
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 363)
    New York State Identification and Intelligence System (NYSIIS) -- general: 1. renumbering penal code 2. privacy
  - Program - General, Legislation, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 364)
    Orange County Districty Attorney.
  - Program, 1971-1972 (Box 34, Folder 365)
    Legislation and annual message, memos, "carryover" legislation, charts.
  - Program - Bonding (Selective) Bill, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 366)
  - Program - Consumer Protection Bills, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 367)
  - Program - Culture and Recreation Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 368)
  - Program - Crime Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 369)
    Press releases, memos, revision of Criminal Procedure Law.
  - Program - Education Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 370)
  - Program - Environment Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 371)
    Memos, bond legislation.
  - Program - Governmental Operations Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 372)
  - Program - Health Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 373)
  - Program - Housing Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 374)
  - Program - Human Rights, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 375)
    Memoranda, bills.
  - Program - Mental Health, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 376)
    Press release, memoranda, bill.
  - Program - Transportation Program Outline, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 377)
  - Program - Public Service Commission, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 378)
  - Program - Railroads, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 379)
    Full crew law -- memos, notes, news articles.
  - Program - Reapportionment, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 380)
    Press releases, Special Session of Legislature on Reapportionment, bills, memos.
  - Program - Real Property Tax (Statewide), 1972 (Box 35, Folder 381)
    Memos, notes and draft legislation to enable cities to tax real estate above constitutional limit.
  - General - Retirement - City of Rochester, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 382)
    Bill to exempt Rochester pensions from current funding costs, notes, memos.
  - General - Insurance Department Study of Public Pension System Supervision, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 383)
    Accounting and investment practices.
  - General - Federal Revune Sharing, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 384)
    Press releases, correspondence.
  - General - Judiciary, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 385)
    Judge Mitchell D. Schweitzer -- removal charges, news clippings.
  - General - Social Services Legislation, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 386)
    Memo and proposed bill making minor technical amendment.
  - General - Agencies "Security and Sensitive", 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 387)
    Memos re: Nelson A. Rockefeller's concerns.
  - General - Special Investigations, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 388)
    a. Frank Adamo -- removal, memorandum b. Department of Environmental Conservation aircraft c. Health Department motor vehicle d. mall security
  - General - Special Investigations, 1971-1972 (Box 35, Folder 389)
    a. Miscellaneous investigations b. Yonkers Raceway -- 5th Race -- Exacta June 7, 1971
  - General - Special Investigations, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 390)
    a. Joseph Calabro b. Albert Stubing State Police investigation files
  - General - State Police Salary Budget Bill, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 391)
  - General - State University of New York (SUNY), 1972 (Box 35, Folder 392)
    a. Miscellaneous b. Local 119 -- food services c. minimum salaries d. equal employment -- discrimination
  - General - Taxation - Evaluation of Gift Tax, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 393)
    Memo on sales tax.
  - General - Teachers' Retirement Legislation - "Departmentals", 1972 (Box 36, Folder 394)
    Benefit bills and memoranda: 72-1 through 72-28; action through April 20, 1972; Legislation package submitted by New York State Teachers' Retirement System.
  - General - Teachers' Retirement System, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 395)
    Memos, legislation action calendar reports.
  - General - Transportation Bond Issue, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 396)
    Nelson A. Rockefeller press releases, litigation papers and correspondence, promotional literature, vote canvass.
  - General - Wage-Price Freeze, 1971; Folder 1 of 3 (Box 36, Folder 397)
    Imposed by President Nixon on August 15, 1971: correspondence.
  - General - Wage-Price Freeze, 1971; Folder 2 of 3 (Box 36, Folder 398)
    Guidelines (Office of Emergency Preparedness).
  - General - Wage-Price Freeze, 1971; Folder 3 of 3 (Box 36, Folder 399)
    Guidelines (newspapers).
  - General - Pension and Retirement, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 400)
    Report of Governor's Committee on the State Employee's Retirement System, May 3, 1969; Department of Civil Service report on retirement matters of 1972.
  - General - New York State Employees' Retirement System, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 401)
    Memos, studies, Nelson A. Rockefeller press releases.
  - General - New York State Employees' Retirement System, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 402)
    Report of The Permanent Commission on Public Employee Pension and Retirement Systems, January 30, 1973.
  - General - New York State Employees' Retirement System, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 403)
    Select Committee on Pensions Reports July 15, 1973, dissenting report, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, memos.
  - General - Retirement Plan Legislative Proposals, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 404)
  - General - Crime Control Planning Board - 1973 Plan, Section 1 (Box 38, Folder 405)
  - General - Crime Control Planning Board - 1973 Plan, Section 2 (Box 38, Folder 406)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Abortion, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 407)
    Correspondence, memos, Nelson A. Rockefeller press release, statistics related to Roe v. Wade (decided January 22, 1973).
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) Suit - Three-Day Messages (Box 39, Folder 408)
    Lawsuit to declare use of Three-Day Messages of Necessity (Emergency) unconstitutional.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Acupuncture, 1972-1973 (Box 39, Folder 409)
    Memos on legislation to permit acupuncture.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Adirondacks, 1971-1972 (Box 39, Folder 410)
    State land master plan proposed by Adirondack Park Agency, 70th Annual Report of the Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks (May 1971).
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Administrative Policy Studies, 1970 (Box 39, Folder 411)
    Academy of Political Science at Columbia University letter to John Lockwood.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Administrative Procedure Act (Law Revision Commission), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 412)
    Law Revision Commission 1967 report; legislative documents, 1966.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Administrative Procedure Act (Law Revision Commission), 1968-1972 (Box 39, Folder 413)
    Correspondence, memos, proposed bill.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Agriculture and Markets, 1972-1974 (Box 40, Folder 414)
    Memo to Nelson A. Rockefeller (August 10, 1972), proposed bill.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Appointment Memos, 1967-1974 (Box 40, Folder 415)
    Memos and Attorney General opinions as to who has power to fill vacancies in various offices.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Council on the Arts, 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 416)
    Memos re: Council 1971 budget, miscellaneous memos.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Audit and Control, 1969 (Box 40, Folder 0416A)
    Ten-year growth pattern memos.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Banking Department, 1970-1972 (Box 40, Folder 417)
    Memos on banking issues, including legal brief on Puerto Rican bank expansion.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Banking - Puerto Rico Banks, etc. (Box 40, Folder 0417A)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted material
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Banking Department Press Release, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 418)
    Report of advisory committee -- "sweeping reforms".
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Battery Park City - Manhattan Landing (Box 40, Folder 419)
    Letter to Nelson A. Rockefeller from Charles Urstadt.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 420)
    Litigation by Berle on constitutionality of budget; petition.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 421)
    Litigation appeal papers.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Big 6 (Cities) Fiscal Program, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 422)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Brooklyn Polytechnic Institute, 1968-1969 (Box 40, Folder 423)
    Budget memos.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Blue Cross Rates, 1969-1970 (Box 40, Folder 424)
    Letter from Insurance Department to Blue Cross re: emergency increase.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Bond Banks (Municipal), 1971-1972 (Box 40, Folder 425)
    Memos re: establishing municipal bond bank.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Boyce Thompson Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 40, Folder 426)
    Correspondence on budget of Institute.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget, 1974 (Box 40, Folder 427)
    Memo on constitutional requirements.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget, 1968 (Box 40, Folder 428)
    Outline, memos, budget message, summary.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget Hearings, 1970-1971 (Box 40, Folder 429)
    Schedule, memos from Assistant Counsels attending department hearings.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Budget - Program Analysis and Review (PAR) Guidelines (Box 40, Folder 430)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Buy American, 1972-1973 (Box 40, Folder 431)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Cable Television, 1970-1973 (Box 41, Folder 432)
    Memos, proposed legislation re: powers of Commission.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Cable Television, 1972-1973 (Box 41, Folder 433)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Calverton Land Purchase, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 434)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Capital District Transportation Authority, 1970-1971 (Box 41, Folder 435)
    Memos re: takeover and operation of United Traction Company.
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Capital Punishment, 1970-1974 (Box 41, Folder 436)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Catskill Study Commission (Box 41, Folder 437)
  - Issues, 1971-1973 - Charitable Solicitations (Box 41, Folder 438)